<u>ray.deng@oscgc.com</u> (929)331-3520

Le Deng Norwood, MA

Summary

Cloud Development, Full Stack, Java, J2EE Platform, Enterprise Web App, Android

Technical Profile

5+ years of experience in enterprise app industry and experienced on programming in Cloud, Mobile/Android, J2EE database and front-end interface. Currently, I'm working as a consultant focusing on web/cloud app solutions for enterprises. In general, I enjoy fast paced working environment, is eager to learn and focus on reliable delivery.

Before that, I have worked for Bleum Software, HP, Synaptics and Allegro Microsystems. During those time, I have gained plenty of experience on enterprise software development and contributed a lot to various products while working in Bleum and HP.

Education

Master of Science, Electrical Engineering Rochester Institute of Technology, USA

Dec, 2011

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical Engineering and Automation Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan China

June, 2006

Skills

A wide variety of skills supporting the architecture and design of enterprise level app solution. My experiences include, but are not limited to:

- 1+ years project-leading experience
- 2+ years cross-platform, full life-cycle commercial software development experience in a small to medium team environment
- 2+ years' experience of OO analysis and design and design patterns

Dev Stack

Front-end: HTML/JavaScript, Angular 2, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI, TypeScript, JQuery, Ajax

Back-end: Java (Oracle Certified), Spring, J2EE, SQL, MySQL, NoSQL/MongoDB **Mobile:** Android, Hybrid/Ionic, Android SDK, Android Studio, Gradle, Google App Publishing

Security: SAML 2.0, OAuth, SSO

Platforms

Linux, Windows, OS X, Mobile/Android/Hybrid, Amazon AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud

Tools

Maven, Gradle, Android Studio, IntelliJ, Git, Jenkins, LoadRunner (Performance Testing), Quality Center (Testing), SVN, Microsoft Office, MS-DOS

ray.deng@oscgc.com (929)331-3520

Work History

7 Years' Industry Experience

OSC Technologies

Consultant

Nov 2015 – present Boston, MA

Working as a full stack consultant on various projects using html/CSS, Bootstrap, JSP, JavaScript, JQuery, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL Database, Apache Storm, Spark and etc.

Allegro Microsystems

Electronic Design Engineer

Aug 2012 – Feb 2016 Manchester, NH

Working in the sensor group to build the high performance IC chip for commercial vehicle clients. Design various building block circuits for advanced hall-effect sensors. Develop models using programming language such as Matlab, Verilog-a. Design testbench to verify circuit sensor product in lab.

Synaptics

Mixed-signal Intern

Jan 2012 – Jul 2012 Rochester, NY

Support design of analog mixed-signal high performance building blocks for LCD display driver IC chips. Develop circuit models using programming language such as Matlab and Verilog to accelerate the development life cycle.

Hewlett-Packard

Software Testing Engineer

Jan 2008 – Jun 2009 Shanghai, China

Working in HP's Global Delivery China Center (GDCC) in Shanghai as a software testing engineer to lead and ensure the reliable delivery of HP's giant ERP system. Working globally with team members from all over the world. Broken done responsibilities include but not limited to developing test cases base on customer requirement; developing test scripts for various functionalities implemented; conducting and supporting test case execution.

Bleum Software

Software Testing Engineer

Sep 2006 – Dec 2007 Shanghai, China

Working in a CMMI certified software company as a software testing engineer to ensure the quality of the products delivered to clients. Exposed in every phase of software development life cycle to lead and ensure the successful delivery of testing conduction of the product. Specifically, develop testing plan in the early phase of project development; develop testing specs to dissect customer requirement; develop test cases based on testing specs; conduct and support test execution; post-mortem analysis to grow the testing team from the experience gained.

ray.deng@oscgc.com (929)331-3520

Projects

Commercial QR Code App - Pure Ticket (Android):

This mobile app is the front-end for an End-to-end eCommerce solution. Staff member can use this app to scan QR code as ticket, coupon, gift and etc, which end-user get from commercial companies. Once scanned, the QR code will be uploaded to cloud for synchronization so that the system knows the QR code has been used.

Technologies:

Technology: Android Studio, Android SDK, QR technology, Cloud/API integration

Identity Access Management System – IoTVerify (With Android):

This project serves as an IAM tool. User logins with a personal NFC tag on android device, which is verified over back-end service. User first registers the tag with the mobile device and once registered, user can login with the registered tag without entering the Username, as it will be discovered by the mobile device automatically. The verification protocol is based on SAML 2.0, which involves Service Provider and Identity Provider as well as communication among the two.

Technologies:

- Technology: Android, SAML2.0/oAuth2.0/Social Identities, NFC, SMS, Java, PHP, MySQL
- NFC device capability for device discovery and registration
- · Mobile security using SAML integration with back-end IdP
- Mobile security using oAuth for social platform integration (such as Google, Okta, etc.)

Apache Storm Project - Psy360:

This is a big data project using Apache Storm for real-time data processing. Captured TV channel usage data is provided from third party to pass to Storm Cluster for data processing. Extracted data will be fed to data analysis team for further management.

Technologies:

Technology: Storm, Java, Amazon Web Service, Amazon S3

Photo Sharing Web App – Lagoon

This is a front-end website project for user to share photos based on the Angular 2 framework. The web app can display different users' photos, show the top-ranked photos, see photo detail, leave comments and etc.

Technologies:

Frontend: Angular 2 Framework, HTML, CSS, TypeScript

Backend: Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring REST, MySQL

E-Commerce Music Store:

This is an E-Commerce Online Music Store Website involving front-end and back-end, where user can browse and search products. User can add products to shopping cart and checkout by filling customer information. User can leave messages asking questions. Admin can manage product inventory. Admin can manage messages left by customer.

Technologies:

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JSP, JavaScript, JQuery

ray.deng@oscgc.com (929)331-3520

· Back-end: Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring Webflow

· Database: Spring Data, JPA, Hibernate, H2

Clinical Management System:

This is a dental clinical system to manage doctor and patient information. Patient can register and book appointment with Doctor. System can track and manage patient diagnosis and treatment data. Doctor can generate customized report from patient data and send to insurance company for review.

Technologies:

Technology: Java, Spring Framework, third party tools such as iText